[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：这是RQ计划的一个例子。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So this is an example of an RQ program.
您可以嵌套数组的形式编写RQ，嵌套数组
You can write RQ in the form of nested arrays which
描述你想用RQ代理的电话做的工作
describe the work that you wanna do with the calls to RQ acting
作为关于并行发生什么，串行发生什么的注释。
as annotations as to what happens in parallel, what happens in serial.
所以这里我们有一个请求，它将并行地做一些事情。
So here we've got one request, that's gonna do stuff in parallel.
同时，它会做几个序列
In parallel, it's gonna do a couple of sequences and
然后是一个独立的东西，一个比赛和一个后备。
then one standalone thing and a race and a fallback.
同时
And simultaneously,
它也会做这个可选的设置，只是类似的东西。
it will also do this optional set, just a similar sort of stuff.
当一切都完成后，
And when it's all done,
然后我们将调用这个函数，这是将显示结果的延续。
we will then call this function that's the continuation which will show the result.
这是一个实际的JavaScript程序，所以让我执行它
So this is an actual JavaScript program, so let me execute it so
你可以看到它的作用。
you can see what it does.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：这些小部件中的每一个都代表一些服务
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So each of these widgets represents some service which is
正在被该程序访问。
being accessed by that program.
所以这些就是立即开始的。
So those are the ones that start immediately.
我可以决定哪一个会成功
And I get to decide which of these are going to succeed and
都会失败。
which are going to fail.
例如，如果我有一个失败，
For example, if I have that one fail,
然后整个请求失败，您可以看到我取消了其他所有内容
then the entire request failed and you can see I cancelled everything else
因为如果整个工作都行不通的话我们就不需要它了。
because we don't need it if the whole job's not gonna work.
所以让我重置一下，我们再试一次。
So let me reset and we'll try it again.
所以假设这一次有一个成功了，好的，我们还在运行，
So let's say this time that one succeeded, okay, we're still running,
一切都很好。
things are good.
这个是可选的，假设它失败了。
This one is optional, let's say it fails.
好吧，它失败了，但没问题，它是可选的，所以我们仍然在运行。
Okay, it failed but no problem, it's optional so we're still running.
假设这个序列开始，这里它是成功的，很好，然后A2开始。
Let's say this sequence starts, here it's successful, good, so then A2 started.
我们完成了请求A1，所以A2开始了。
We got the request A1 finished so A2 starts.
你对B1做类似的事情，成功了，所以B2现在正在运行。
You do a similar thing with B1, that succeeded, so B2 is now running.
我们有一场D1，D2，D3的比赛，哪一个应该赢？
We've got a race with D1, D2, D3, which one should win?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：2。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: 2.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克罗克福德(Douglas Crockford)：2。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: 2.
所以第二场比赛赢了。
So race 2 wins.
我们取消了D1和D3，因为我们不再需要那些结果了。
And we canceled D1 and D3 because we don't need those results any more.
假设我们的后备失败了，这不是问题。
Let's say our fallback fails, not a problem.
回退中的下一步成功。
The next step in the fallback succeeds.
我可以按任何顺序完成这些。
And I can finish these in any order.
这么说吧，也许这成功了
So let's say that goes and maybe that succeeds and
成功了，我们现在很好。
that succeeds, that succeeds and we're now good.
所以在这一点上，整个事情都完成了。
So at that point the whole thing finished.
所有尚未完成的可选项目，
All of the optional things that were still pending,
那些被取消了我们就完事了。
those got canceled and we're done.
有什么问题吗？
Any questions about that?
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：是的，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Yeah,
你能给我们一个真实世界的例子来说明你会在哪里使用它吗？
could you give us a real world example of where you'd use this?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，我会的，我一直在这么做。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, I will, and I've been sort of doing that.
所以我举了例子，我们得到了导航，我们得到了广告，所有这些。
So I gave examples that we get the nav and we get the ads and all of those.
那些都是现实世界的东西。
Those are real world things.
这些就是您在Web应用程序中将拥有的流的种类。
Those are the sorts of flows that you would have in a web application.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：他们想要3个广告，但12个中的任何一个都可以在那里加载，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: They want 3 ads but any of 12 could load there,
只需要前3个？
it'll just take the first 3?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：当然，你可以做这些事情，无论你需要什么。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Sure, you can do those sorts of things, whatever you need.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：这又是一个实现了这一点的程序。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So this again is the program that accomplished that.
所有这些行为都发生在处理这些内容的RQ函数中。
All of that behavior happened just in the RQ functions handling that stuff.
所以你可以用很多方法来组合这些东西。
So and you can compose these things in lots of ways.
例如，这是一个序列，我们将做一件事
For example, this is a sequence in which we'll do one thing and
我们会得到它的结果，我们会把它传递给三个不同的东西，他们会
we'll take its result and we'll pass that to three different things, and they will
将所有结果累加到一个数组中，并将该数组传递给最后一个数组。
accumulate all of their results into an array and pass that array to the last one.
这样你就可以得到很多工作流程。
So you can get lots of workflows.
所以
So for
一个真实世界的例子，这是我最近一直在做的事情。
a real world example, this is the most recent thing that I've been working on.
我正在写一本百科全书。
I'm working on an encyclopedia.
我正在用一种创作语言写作
And I'm writing in a authoring language and
这是我在节点中运行的过程，用于构建图书。
this is the process that I run in node for building the book.
所以我首先读取文件并将结果传递给include
So I first read the file and I pass that result to the include
处理器，处理所有包含文件的内容。
processor which handles the stuff with all the include files.
然后我把它传递给一个东西，然后它会编译它并生成HTML。
And then I pass it to a thing which will then compile it and produce the HTML.
然后我有另一件事，然后将它写出到文件系统。
And then I have another thing which will then write it out to the file system.
所以这是一个序列，一件事发生在另一件事上。
So this is a sequence, one thing happens to another.
但它不是作为嵌套的事件处理程序编写的，
But it's not being written as nested event handlers,
它被写成一张清单，列出了一件又一件发生的事情。
it's written as a list of things that happen one thing after another.
所以它看起来更像是一个程序。
So it looks more like a program.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：什么是回拨？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: What's the callback?
回调的，是下一个函数的回调，
The callback's, is the callback the next function,
或-&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：回调是
or- &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: The callback is
类似于我们今天早上用Continue WISE所做的事情。
similar to the thing that we did with continue wise this morning.
这是会收到结果的东西。
It's the thing that will receive the result.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以这是延续传递风格的特例
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So this is a special case of continuation passing style where
在每一步，我们不返回结果，
at each step, we don't return the result,
相反，我们将结果传递给提供给我们的函数。
instead we pass the result to a function that's provided to us.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 4：[咳嗽]，最终回调本质上是控制台日志吗？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: [COUGH] And final callback is essentially a console log?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，最后一个会将它发送到控制台。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, the last one will send it to the console.
&gt；&gt；演讲者3：总之，这是你的节目，对吗？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Anyway, this is your program, right?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yep.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：所以这个要排序的第一个函数，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So this first function to sequence,
首先它将调用第一个函数
first it's gonna call the first function and
它将调用第二个函数，然后调用第三个和第四个函数。
it's gonna call the second function and then the third and the fourth.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：对。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Right.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 3：其中第一个是传入的回调的值
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Where's the first, the value of callback that gets passed into
第一个函数，它是从哪里来的？
the first function, where's that come from?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：它将被调用，所以
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: It'll be called by, so
我在这里没有展示的是RQ.sequence返回一个函数。
what I didn't show here is that RQ.sequence returns a function.
当我们调用该函数时，
When we call that function,
然后它将调用这个列表中的第一个，为它提供一个回调函数。
it will then call the first in this list providing a callback function to it.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 3：这就是使它调用第二个的钩子。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: And that's the hook that makes it call the second one.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：对。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Right.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 3：某种RQ.sequence类型总是自己传递
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Sort of RQ.sequence kind of always passes itself
插入到它调用的每个函数中？
into each of the functions that it calls?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：差不多，是的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Sort of, yeah.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：好的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Okay.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 5：它传递上一个[INAUDIBLE]的值。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 5: It passes the value from the previous [INAUDIBLE].
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，所以-&gt；&gt；扬声器3：那，好的，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, so- &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: That, okay,
你之前提到过，是的。
you mentioned that earlier, yeah.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：对，所以你可以想到它。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Right, so you can think of it.
它有点像一根管子，它把东西穿过，所以
It's sort of like a pipe that's passing the stuff through so
每个人都从前一个人那里得到了东西。
each gets the thing from the previous one.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：这不是节点。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: And this is not node.
这只是纯JS
This is just pure JS.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：对，这是纯JS。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Right, this is pure JS.
如果你有异步的话你也可以在浏览器上运行它
You could run this on a browser as well if you've got asynchronous
那里有事情要做。
things to do there.
它也会跑的。
It would run as well.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：是的，它不是一个模块，它只是一个全局模块。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Yeah, it's not a module, it's just a global.
RS将是一个全局或任何你声明它的地方。
RS would be a global or wherever you declare it.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：这只是一个JS文件，您可以随心所欲地加载它。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: It's just a JS file, you can load it however you want.
&GT；&GT；扬声器3：它只是一个JS。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: It's just a JS.
但是，它在名称空间中创建名为RS的全局。
It creates global, though, called RS in the namespace.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：在浏览器中，它创建一个全局命名空间并
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: In a browser it creates a global namespace and
在节点中，它将添加一些内容。
in node it will add something.
是的，它会作为模型出口。
Yeah, it'll export as a model.
因此RQ也可以处理超时。
So RQ can also deal with timeouts.
所以这些函数中的每一个也将花费以毫秒为单位的时间，这表示，
So each of those functions will also take a time in milliseconds which says,
这需要在这么多时间内成功完成，否则我们将失败。
this needs to complete successfully in this much time or we will fail it.
在并行的情况下，还可以指定untiliseconds，
In the case of the parallel, you can also specify untiliseconds,
这给出了可选集合。
which gives the optional set.
在你被取消之前你还有这么多时间，所以
You got this much time until you get cancelled, so
以防主要的工作提前结束。
just in case that the main ones finish early.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：那么我们也可以处理取消。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Then we can also deal with cancellation.
因此任何请求者函数都可以有选择地返回Cancel函数，并且
So any requestor function can optionally return a cancel function, and
调用Cancel函数时，它将尝试取消请求。
that cancel function when it is called will attempt to cancel the request.
不能保证取消会在请求完成之前发生，
There's no guarantee that the cancellation will happen before the request completes,
因为它们可以是网络竞赛和其他正在进行的事情。
because they can be network races and other things going on.
所以它的目的是停止不必要的工作。
So it's intended to stop unnecessary work.
这不是撤销，也不是回滚。
It's not an undo, it's not a rollback.
此外，如果您正在尝试取消交易，对于
And also if you're trying to cancel a transaction, for
例如，这不是您想要执行的取消操作。
example, this is not the cancellation that you want to do.